spoutable.com 2017-12-30

# Spoutable Privacy Policy

Our privacy policy is designed to provide transparency into our privacy practices and principles, in a format that our guests can navigate, read and understand. We are dedicated to treating your personal information with care and respect. As such, we have created and implemented this privacy policy to inform visitors to the Spoutable website and users of the Spoutable features how we collect, protect and use the information we gather.

This website is offered by Spoutable LLC (collectively “we”, “our” or “us”). If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#b5c0c5c5dac7c1f5c6c5dac0c1d4d7d9d09bd6da).

#### 1\. Information Collected

We collect information to provide better services to our users and improve our overall product effectiveness. We collect information in two ways:

 _Information you provide to us_ : Some of our services, such as those we provide to advertisers and publishers, require you to sign up for a Spoutable account. When you sign up, we will ask you for personal information including your name, email address, and other information; in some cases we may ask you for billing information.

 _Information we derive from your use of our website and by viewing our sponsored content_ : We may collect information about the services that you use and how you use them, like when you visit different parts of our website or view our sponsored content, and what selections you make. We may also automatically collect certain technical information about your:

  * Device - We may collect device-specific information (such as your model #, operating system version, unique identifiers, mobile information if you use a mobile device to access our site or our service).
  * Site Activity - When you use our services or view content provided by us, we may automatically collect and store certain information in server logs, including how you use our service, your internet protocol address, the date and time of your request and referral URL and cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account. Cookies are small bits of electronic information that a website can transfer to a visitor’s computer to help target message and keep records of the users visit to a website. The use of cookies is standard on the Internet and many web sites use them. Cookies allow web site operators to better customize visits to the site to the visitor’s individual preferences. For example, by setting a cookie you would not have to enter information in the Site more than once, thereby saving time. We do not receive or record any personally identifying information in the cookies we use. Although most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can usually change your browser to prevent that or to notify you when you are sent a cookie. Even without accepting a cookie, you can still access the Spoutable Features.

#### 2\. Use of Collected Information

Your personally identifiable information may be used to: analyze how the service is used, diagnose service or technical problems or maintain security; operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service; fulfill requests you may make of us; personalize your experience; and provide you with information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting. The information we collect may be used to target ads.

We may use the information we collect from our advertiser and publisher customers for billing and account communication purposes. If you contact us, we may keep a record of your communication to help solve any issues you might be facing. We may use your email address to inform you about our services, such as letting you know about upcoming changes or improvements. Generally speaking, we use the information we collect from all of our services to provide, maintain, protect and improve our services, to develop new services and offerings and to protect us and our users. You can opt out of any email communications you no longer wish to receive. 

#### 3\. Information Sharing

We do not share personally identifiable information with companies, outside organizations and individuals unless one of the following circumstances apply:

 _For targeting_

We perform cookie syncing to allow other third party advertising networks to target advertisements to you through our service.

 _For external processing_

We provide personal information to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us or to process billing on our behalf, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other reasonable confidentiality and security measures.

 _With your consent_

We will share personal information with companies, outside organizations or individuals if we have your consent to do so.

 _For legal reasons_

We may transfer and disclose your personal information, to third parties to comply with certain legal obligations when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify, enforce or apply our terms of use or other applicable policies; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of Spoutable, our customers or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

 _In case of a sale or asset transfer_

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of our assets, user information, including personal information collected from our business partners through their use of our services, could be included in the transferred assets. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable means to notify you, either through email and/or a prominent notice on the services.

We may collect and share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners such as businesses we have a relationship with, advertisers, content publishers, or connected sites.  For example, we may share information to show trends about the general use of our services.

#### 4\. Information Security

Given that the security of your information is important to us, we use commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through our service. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from us, at all times. Notwithstanding the foregoing measures, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or guarantee that information on the service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed. Your privacy settings may also be affected by changes to the functionality of our distributors, such as social networks. We are not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party.

#### 5\. Other Important Information

Third Party Websites

Our service may contain links to other websites that we do not own or operate. This includes links from customers, sponsors and partners that may use our logo(s) as part of a co-branding agreement. We do not control, recommend or endorse and are not responsible for these sites or their content, products, services or privacy policies or practices. These other web sites may send their own cookies to your device, they may independently collect data or solicit Personal Information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. You should also independently assess the authenticity of any site that appears or claims that it is a part of this service.

Updating Your Personal Information

All registered users are able to review, update or correct their personally identifiable information provided during the account registration process by changing their "user preferences" in their account. If you choose to opt out entirely, then your account may become deactivated and you will need to re-register should you decide to opt-in again. To delete your account entirely, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) You understand and agree we are not able to remove your personally identifiable information from the records of any third party who has been provided with your information in compliance with the use and sharing policy outlined above.

Enforcement

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy. When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up.

Children

Our service is not directed towards children under the age of 13. As such, we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13 years of age. If we determine upon collection that a user is under 13, we will not use or maintain his/her personal information without the parent/guardian’s consent. If we become aware we have unknowingly collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our records.

Location

Our website and associated services are hosted in the United States.  If you are outside of the United States, your information will be processed and stored in the United States and you are consenting to such processing and storage.

Updates

From time to time, we may change this privacy policy to accommodate new technologies, industry practices, regulatory requirements or for other purposes.  You should check back here periodically to see if the Privacy Policy has been updated. We will show the date of the latest update to the Privacy Policy at the bottom of the page so you can tell when it was last updated.

Contact

We regularly review our compliance with this privacy policy. Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f39a9d959cb380839c868792919f96dd909c9e) or by mail to Spoutable LLC, 1929 Hancock Street, #200, San Diego CA 92037, Attn: Privacy Policy Dept.

Updated April 1, 2017
